Guide to the Protestant Episcopal Bishops Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Protestant Episcopal Bishops collection
1740-1950
MS 21
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5
(12 boxes, 1 folio)
Correspondence from and subject files relating to the bishops of the Protestant Episcopal Church and the Protestant Episcopal Church in the United States and Europe.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Kenneth W. Cameron and others, 1936-
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: I. Correspondence. II. Subject File.
Scope and Contents
The Protestant Episcopal Bishops Collection consists of those manuscripts (originally in three volumes) deposited for the Berkeley Divinity School Library by Dean William P. Ladd in 1936 and 1940, manuscripts given to Yale Library by the Rev. Doctor Kenneth W. Cameron and other sources, and letters to the Rev. Melancthon Lloyd Woolsey (1855-1940). There are roughly 2500 items in 485 folders, housed in 12 grey boxes and one oversize folio.
The collection is divided into two series. Series I, CORRESPONDENCE, is subdivided into American and non-American Bishops, followed by one folder of non-Bishop letters. Approximately 450 Bishops are represented, some only by autographs and/or photographs, but most have five or six letters as well in their folders. For each Bishop the following information is given, where known: full name, longevity, state or territory of diocese, dates of correspondence, number of items in the folder. Material which is not strictly correspondence, such as sermons, lengthy newsclippings, pamphlets, speeches, etc., is indicated for each folder in the register.
The two largest groups of letters belong to Bishop Seabury, the first American Bishop, and Bishop John Williams, 3rd Bishop of Connecticut. Of the 50 pieces in the Bishop Seabury group, many are photostatic copies of letters and documents obtained from the New York State Historical Society. The 125 items in the Bishop Williams section are mostly letters to his cousin; also included are sermons, notebooks, and diplomas. Perhaps also of interest is the collection of orders of consecration of 44 Bishops, found under Bishop Tuttle. The terminal dates of this first subdivision are roughly 1775-1937, although some material dates from 1740 to 1954. The bulk of the section falls between 1820 and 1940.
In the second part of Series I, some 32 non-American Bishops are represented, usually by an autograph or a single letter. Most of the Bishops are from England or Ireland. This relatively small subdivision is followed by a single folder of non-Bishop letters, all but two of which were addressed to Woolsey.
Series II, the SUBJECT FILE, is divided into four parts. The first two, as above, concern American and non-American Bishops respectively. The American section contains autographs and photographs, a printed table of the succession of Bishops (Nos. 1-396), and the register and letter journal of Foster Ely, who first assembled the letters of various Bishops. The non-American section also contains autographs and pictures from magazines, and, much more important historically, the reply of the English Bishops to the American request for Episcopal status in 1786. The next two parts concern Trinity Church in New Haven and St. Bartholomew's Church in New York. The former contains lease agreements with the Scott family from 1814-1881; documents of the rector, Reuben Sherwood; the 1831 cornerstone inscription; and records of the Sunday School Teachers Society from 1830-1840. St. Bartholomew's Church is represented by only one folder containing a hard-bound volume on its history by E. Clowes Chorley, 1935. A folder of mi
For anyone interested in American Church history in general, and the Episcopal Church in particular, this collection should be of great interest. It not only provides unusual insights into the personal lives of the men who operated at the highest levels of the ecclesiastical hierarchy, but also contains rich resources for the history of church doctrine and the movement of theology through a vast social and political spectrum. Of salient importance is the section of letters and documents of Bishop Samuel Seabury and associates from a time of revolutionary change for the church as well as the country. Also of interest are the missionary Bishops in the various western states and abroad, for these men were literally the pioneers of the church in the 19th and early 20th centuries. No matter what period one investigates within this two hundred year era of the church, this collection will remain of continuing historical interest and importance.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Episcopal Church -- Clergy; Episcopal Church -- History; Autographs; Clergy; Bedell, Gregory Thurston, 1817-1892; Brewster, Benjamin, 1860-1941; Coleman, Leighton, 1837-1907; Coxe, A. Cleveland (Arthur Cleveland), 1818-1896; Doane, George Washington, 1799-1859; Doane, William Croswell, 1832-1913; Dudley, T. U. (Thomas Underwood), 1837-1904; Grafton, Charles C. (Charles Chapman), 1830-1912; Hall, A. C. A. (Arthur Crawshay Alliston), 1847-1930; Lawrence, William, 1850-1941; Manning, William Thomas, Bp., 1866-1949; Meade, William, 1789-1862; Onderdonk, Henry U. (Henry Ustick), 1789-1858; Perry, James De Wolfe, 1871-; Potter, Alonzo, 1800-1865; Potter, Henry Codman, 1834-1908; Potter, Horatio, 1802-1887; Seabury, Samuel, 1729-1796; Seymour, George F. (George Franklin), 1829-1906; Starkey, Thomas Alfred, 1818-1903; Stevens, William Bacon, 1815-1887; Tucker, Henry St. George, 1874-1959; Tuttle, Daniel Sylvester, 1837-1923; Whittingham, William Rollinson, 1805-1879; Williams, J. (John), 1817-1899; Woolsey, Melancthon Lloyd, 1955-
- Correspondence, Series I
  - American Bishops
    - Abbott, Henry Pryor Almon 1881-, (Ky.) (1), 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ablewhite, Haywood Seller, 1887-, (Marquette, Mich.) (3), 1937 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Acheson, Edward Campion 1858-1934, (Conn.) (2), 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Adams, William Forbes 1833-1920, (Md.) (9), 1892-1893, 1897-1898, 1903, 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Anderson, Charles Palmerston 1863-1930, (Chicago) (8), 1906-1908, 1915, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Armitage, William Edmond 1830-1873, (Wisc.) (8), 1862, 1869, 1871-1873 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Atkinson, Thomas 1807-1881, (N.C.) (5), 1852, 1855, 1866, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Atwill, Douglass Henry 1881-, (N.Dak.) (2), 1935, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Atwill, Edward Robert 1840-1911, (W.Mo.) (6), 1893, 1902-1903, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Atwood, Julius Walter 1857-1945 (Ariz.) (14), 1910, 1912-1913, 1920, 1928, 1937, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Auer, John Gottlieb 1832-1874 (5), 1864, 1867, 1871, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Aves, Henry Damerel 1853-1936, (Mexico) (5), 1906-1907, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Babcock, Samuel Gavitt 1851-, (Mass.) (7), 1913, 1921, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Baker, Richard H. (N.C.) (1), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Barker, William Morris 1854-1901, (Wash.) (9), 1889, 1892, 1895-1896, 1898, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Barnwell, Robert Woodward 1849-1902, (Ala.) (5), 1899,1901-1902 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Barry, Frederick (Albany, N.Y.) (1), 1950 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bartlett, Frederick Bethune 1882-, (Ida.) (7), Autograph, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      General
      Deacon Exam Notebooks, 1907-1908
    - Bass, Edward 1726-1803, (Mass.) (4), 1797-1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Sermon (40mss.pp), 1766
    - Beal, Harry (3) 1885-1944, (Panama Canal Zone) (3), 1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Beckwith, Charles Minnigerode 1851-1928, (Ala.) (6), 1900, 1904, 1906, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Beckwith, John Watrus 1831-1890, (Ga.) (7), 1881,1883, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Bedell, Gregory Thurston, 1817-1892, (Ohio) (31), 1860, 1862, 1868, 1871, 1874, 1876, 1878, 1882-1884, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Beecher, George Allen 1868-, (W.Neb.) (11), 1910-1912, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bennett, Granville Gaylord 1882-, (R.I.) (2), 1941, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Bentley, John Boyd (Alaska) (1), 1937 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Biller, George, Jr. 1874-1915, (S.Dak.) (7), 1910, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Binsted, Norman Spencer (Tohoku, Japan) (2), 1937 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Bissell, William Henry Augustus 1814, 1893 (7), 1878, 1884, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Bliss, George Yemens 1874-1924, (Vt.) (10), 1915-1916, 1918, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Block, Karl Morgan, (Cal.) (2), 1950 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Bloy, Francis Irving (L.A.,Cal.) (1), 1950 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Boone, William Jones 1811-1864, (China) (5), 1841, 1859-1860 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Boone, William Jones 1846-1891, (China) (3), 1884, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Bowen, Nathaniel 1779-1839, (S.C.) (4), 1819, 1837-1838 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Bowman, Samuel 1800-1861, (Penn.) (6), 1849, 1858, 1860, n. d. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Bratton, Theodore DuBose 1862-1944, (Miss.) (7), 1903-1904, 1906, 1910, 1916, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Brent, Charles Henry 1862-1929, (N.Y.) (13), 1901, 1904, 1908, 1911-1912, 1919, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Brewer, Leigh Richmond 1839-1916, (Montana) (7), 1883-1884, 1886, 1893, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Brewster, Benjamin 1860-1941, (Maine) (48), 1909, 1912-1913, 1915-1916, 1918-1923, 1925-1927, 1929-1930, 1932, 1937, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Brewster, Chauncey Bund 1848-1941, (Conn.) (19), 1893-1894, 1898, 1904, 1906, 1911, 1916, 1919, 1927, 1929, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Brooke, Francis Key 1852, 1918, (Okla.) (7), 1902, 1909, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Brooks, Phillips 1835-1893, (Mass.) (9), 1869, 1884, 1890, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Brown, John Henry Hobart 1831-1888 (Fond duLac, Wisc.) (13), 1876, 1881, 1883-1884, 1886-1887, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Brown, William Cabell 1861-1927, (Va.) (1), 1919 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Brown, William Montgomery 1855-, (Ark.) (6), 1903-1904, 1907, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Brown, Wyatt (Penn.) (1), 1937 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Brownell, Thomas Church 1779-1865, (Conn.) (8), 1820, 1823, 1827-1828, 1838, 1861, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Budlong, Frederick Grandy 1881-, (Conn.) (11), 1929, 1934, 1937-1938, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Burch, Charles Sumner 1855-1920, (N.Y.) (10), 1911-1913, 1916, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Burgess, Alexander 1819-1901, (Quincey, Ill.) (6), 1881, 1885, 1893, 1898, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Burgess, Frederick 1853-1925, (L.I.,N.Y.) (9), 1904-1905, 1907-1910, 1923, n-d. (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Burgess, George 1809-1966, (Maine) (6), 1845, 1856-1857, 1862, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Burrill, Gerald F. (Dallas, Tex.) (2), 1950 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Burton, Lewis William 1852-1940, (Ky.) (14), 1894, 1897-1898, 1903, 1907-1908, 1913, 1916, 1922, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Campbell, Robert Erskine 1884-, (Liberia) (3), 1933, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Campbell, Wilburn Camrock (W.Va.) (1), 1950 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Capers, Ellison 1837-1908, (S.C.), 1903-1904, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Capers, William Theodotus 1867-, (W. Texas) (4), 1919, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Carpenter, Charles Colcock Jones 1899-, (Ala.) (2), 1939 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Carson, Harry Roberts 1869-, (Haiti) (3), 1924, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Casady, Thomas 1881-, (Okla.) (2), 1937 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Chase, Carlton 1794-1870, (N.H.) (6), 1818, 1848, 1861, 1866 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Chase, Philander 1775-1852, (Ill.) (11), 1830, 1839, 1842-1843, 1850-1852 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Cheshire, Joseph Blount 1850-1932,(N.C.) (10), 1894-1895, 1898, 1903, 1910, 1915, 1919, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Claggett, Thomas John 1742-1816 (3), 1800, 1815 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Clark, Stephen Cutter 1892-, (Utah) (1), 1949 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Clark, Thomas March 1812-1903, (R.I.) (10), 1842, 1871, 1883, 1889, 1898, 1902, undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Clarkson, Robert Harper 1826-1884, (Neb.) (6), 1837, 1860, 1866, 1876, undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Clingman, Charles 1883-, (Ky.) (2), 1937, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Cobbs, Nicholas Hamner 1796-1861, (Ala.) (5), 1845, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Codman, Robert 1859-1915, (Maine) (7), 1901, 1908-1909, 1915, undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Coleman, Leighton 1836-1907, (Del.) (49), 1875, 1880, 1889-1893, 1895, 1899, 1902-1903, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Coley, Edward Huntington 1861-, (Cen. N.Y.) (12), 1922, 1925-1929, 1937, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Colmore, Charles Blayney 1879-1950 (Puerto Rico) (11), 1913, 1915, 1926, 1930, 1937-1938, 1941, undated (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Cook, Philip (Del.) (7), 1921, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Coxe, Arthur Cleveland 1818-1896, (W.N.Y.) (26), 1844, 1848, 1855, 1865, 1866, 1876, 1878, 1882-1887, 1890, 1894, 1896, undated (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Crawshay, Arthur 1847-1930 (1), 1893 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Creighton, Frank Whittington 1879-, (Mexico) (5), 1931, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Croes, John 1762-1832, (N.J.) (5), 1823, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 80)
      Sermon: Ps.130:3-4 (28mss.pp), n.d.
    - Cross, Edward Makin, (Spokane, wash.) (1), 1937 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Cummins, George David 1822-1876 (7), 1858-1859, 1862, 1867, 1872-1873 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Dagwell, Benjamin Dunlap (Oregon) (3), undated (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Dallas, John Thompson 1880-, (N.H.) (16), 1937 (Box 2, Folder 84)
      Deacon's Exam notebooks (12), 1909
    - Daniels, Henry H. (Mont.) (5), 1926-1927, 1929, 1930, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Darlington, James Henry 1856-1930, (Penn.) (12), 1883, 1905-1906, 1908-1909, 1912, 1916, 1920, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Darst, Thomas Campbell 1875-, (N.C.) (6), 1915, 1919, 1937, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Davenport, George W. (Easton, Md.) (1), 1937 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Davies, Thomas Frederick 1831-1905, (Mich.) (13), 1871, 1881, 1892-1893, 1898,1900-1902, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Davies, Thomas Frederick, Jr. 1872-1936, (W.Mass.) (11), 1911-1913, 1915-1916, 1921, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Davis, Cameron J. (W.N.Y.) (4), 1937 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Davis, Thomas Frederick 1804-1871, (S.C.) (5), 1854-1855 (Box 2, Folder 92)
      [one by his daughter, 1911]
    - Dehon, Theodore 1776-1817, (S.C.) (3), 1811, undated (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Delancey, William Heathcote 1797-1865, (W.N.Y.) (8), 1835, 1839, 1851, 1854, 1858, 1860 (Box 2, Folder 94)
      [includes list of deacons, 1839-1849]
    - Demby, Edward Thomas 1869-, (Ark.)(1), 1921 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - DeWolfe, James Pernette 1895-, (L.I.,N.Y.) (3), 1942 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Doane, George Washington 1799-1859 (N.J.) (19), 1832, 1834, 1836, 1839-1841, 1843-1844, 1849, 1855 (Box 2, Folder 97)
      [Pamphlet: "Bishop Doane's Argument Before the Court of Bishops," Newark, 1852, 16pp]
    - Doane, William Croswell 1832-1913, (Albany, N.Y.) (29), 1869-1870, 1874, 1876, 1882-1883, 1886-1888, 1898, 1902-1903, 1905-1908, nd (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Donegan, Horace (N.Y.) (2), 1949, undated (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Dudley, Thomas Underwood 1837-1904, (Ky.) (38), 1875-1876, 1885, 1892-1901, 1803, undated (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Du Moulin, Frank 1870-,(Ohio) (3), 1913, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Dun, Angus (Washington) (1), undated (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Dunlop, George Kelley 1830-1888, (N.M.) (6), 1880-1881, 1884, 1886 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Eastburn, Manton 1801-1872, (Mass.) (8), 1840, 1843, 1849, 1855-1856, 1862 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Edsall, Samuel Cook 1860-1917, (Minn.) (7), 1902-1903, 1905, 1907, 1909, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Elliott, Robert Woodward Barnwell 1840-1887, (W. Texas) (6), 1884, 1886-1887 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Elliott, Stephen 1806-1866, (S.C.) (5), 1836, 1840, 1845, 1851 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Emery, Richard Runkel (N.Dak.) (3), 1934, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Emrich, Richard Stanley Merrill 1910-, (Mich.) (1), 1950 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Essex, William Leopold (Quincy, Ill.) (1), 1937 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Faber, William Frederic, 1860-1934, (Mont.) (1) (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Fawcett, M. Edward 1865-1935, (Quincy, Ill.) (6), 1904-1907 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Fenner, Goodrich R. (Kans.)(2), 1937 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Ferguson, Samuel David 1842-1916, (Liberia) (5), 1902, 1904, 1908, undated (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Ferris, David Lincoln 1864-, (W.N.Y.) (11), 1921-1924, 1927-1929, 1931, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Finlay, Kirkman G. (S.C.) (2), undated (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Fiske, Charles 1868-1942, (Cen.N.Y.) (5), 1917, 1935, 1937, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Fox, Herbert Henry Haywood 1871-, (Mont.) (2), 1937 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Francis, Joseph Marshall 1862-1939, (Indianapolis, Ind.) (8), 1903-1904, 1906-1907, 1913, 1917, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Freeman, George Washington 1789-1858 (5), 1843-1844, 1848 (Box 3, Folder 120)
      [Confirmation sermon, 31mss.pp, n.d.]
    - Freeman, James Edward 1866-, (Wash., D.C.) (5), 1937 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Funsten, James Bowen 1856-1918, (Idaho) (7), 1903, 1906, 1908-1909, 1911, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Gadsden, Christopher Edwards 1785-1852 (6), 1841, 1851, undated (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Gailor, Thomas Frank 1856-1935, (Tenn.) (14), 1881, 1893, 1895,1903, 1907, 1909, 1915, 1919, 1921, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Galleher, John Nichols 1839, 1891, (Louisiana) (5), 1880, 1886, 1888 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Gardner, Wallace John 1883-, (N.J.) (3), 1937, undated (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Garland, Thomas James 1866-1931, (Penn.) (9), 1911-1913, 1921, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Garrett, Alexander Charles 1832-1924, (N. Texas) (8), 1911-1913, 1921, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Gesner, Conrad Herbert (Minn.) (5), 1934-1936 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Gibson, Robert Atkinson 1846-1919, (Va.) (8), 1900, 1904-1905, 1911-1912, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Gibson, Robert Fisher, Jr. (Va.) (1), 1949 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Gilbert, Charles Kendall 1878-, (N.Y.) (5), 1937-1938, undated (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Gilbert, Mahlon Norris 1848-1900, (Minn.) (6), 1890, 1893, 1897, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Gillespie, George De Normandie 1819-1909, (W.Mich.) (7), 1877, 1988, 1994, 1998, 1903-1904 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Gilman, Alfred A. (Hankow, China) (2), undated (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Gooden, Robert Burton 1874-, (L.A., Cal.) (4), 1937 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Goodwin, Frederick Deane (Va.) (5), 1934, 1937, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Grafton, Charles Chapman 1832-1912, (Fond du Lac, Wisc.) (24), 1885, 1887, 1898, 1900-1901, 1903-1904, undated (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Gravatt, William Loyall 1858-, (W.Va.) (11), 1904, 1909, 1911, 1930, 1932, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Graves, Anson Rogers 1842-1931, (Neb.) (7), 1892, 1906-1908, undated (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Graves, Frederick Robers, 1858-, (Shanghai) (10), 1901, 1903, 1907, 1915, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Gray, Campbell (N.Ind.) (2), 1937 (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Gray, William Crane 1835-1919, (S. Fla.) (8), 1892, 1895, 1898, 1903, 1809, 1813 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Green, William Mercer 1798-1887, (Miss.) (5), 1878-1879, 1883, 1887 (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - Green, William Mercer [II.] 1876-, (Miss.) (5), 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Greer, David Hummel 1844-1919, (N.Y.) (8), 1886, 1903-1905, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - Gregg, Alexander 1819-1893, (Tex.) (8), 1878, 1881, 1889-1891 (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - Gribbin, Robert Emmet 1887-, (W.N.C.) (3), 1934, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Griswold, Alexander Viets 1766-1843, (Mass.) (6), 1823, 1830, 1832, 1834 (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - Griswold, Sheldon Munson 1861-1930, (Chicago) (7), 1902-1904, 1907, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - Guerry, William Alexander 1861-1928, (S.C.) (5), 1907-1909 (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - Hale, Charles Reuben 1827-1900, (Ill.) (6), 1882, 1885, 1895, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - Hall, Arthur Crawshay Alliston 1847-1930, (Vt.) (73), 1898-1907, 1909, 1912-1913, 1915-1927, undated (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - Hall, Charles Francis (N.H.) (1), undated (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - Harding, Alfred 1852-1923, (Wash.,D.C.) (9), 1906, 1909-1911, 1919-1921 (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - Hare, William Hobart 1838-1909, (S.Dak.) (8), 1881, 1888, 1898, 1903, 1907-1908 (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - Harris, Bravid Washington 1896-, (Liberia) (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 157)
    - Harris, Samuel Smith 1841-1888, (Mich.) (9), 1874, 1879-1880, 1884 (Box 4, Folder 158)
    - Hart, Oliver J. (Penn.) (1), 1942 (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - Hawks, Cicero Stephens 1844-1868, (Mo.) (5), 1842, 1862, 1866-1867 (Box 4, Folder 160)
    - Helfenstein, Edward Trail 1865-, (Md.) (2), 1933, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 161)
    - Henshaw, John Prentiss Kewley 1792-1852, (R.I.) (5), 1821, 1828, 1851-1852 (Box 4, Folder 162)
    - Heron, Raymond A. (Mass.). (2), 1937 (Box 4, Folder 163)
    - Hobart, John Henry 1775-1830, (N.Y.) (7), 1805, 1818, 1825, 1829 (Box 4, Folder 164)
    - Hobson, Henry Wise 1891-, (S. Ohio) (13), 1932, 1934, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 165)
      [Notes on mss. "Southern Ohio and its Bishop," 1932, 7mss.pp; welcoming address, 1937, 3mss.pp]
    - Holly, James Theodore (Haiti) (3), 1884, 1889 (Box 4, Folder 166)
    - Hopkins, John Henry 1792-1868, (Vt.) (11), 1832, 1841, 1853-1855, 1858, 1860, 1866 (Box 4, Folder 167)
    - Horner, Junius Moore 1859-1933, (N.C.) (6), 1902-1903, 1907-1908 (Box 4, Folder 168)
    - Howden, Frederick Bingham 1869-, (N.M.) (9), 1913-1914, 1931, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - Howe, Mark Antony de Wolfe 1809-1895, (Cen.Penn.) (8), 1847, 1850, 1878, 1887, 1891, undated (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - Howe, William Bell White 1823-1894, (S.C.) (5), 1873, 1885, 1887 (Box 4, Folder 171)
    - Hulse, Hiram Richard 1868-, (Cuba) (4), 1892, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 172)
    - Huntington, Daniel Trumbull 1868-, (Anking, China) (5), 1912, 1914, 1926, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 173)
    - Huntington, Frederick Dan 1819-1904, (Cen. N.Y.) (12), 1855, 1858, 1871, 1873-1874, 1883-1884, 1899, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 174)
    - Huston, S. Arthur (Wash.) (2), 1937 (Box 4, Folder 175)
    - Ingle, James Addison 1867-1903, (Hankow, China) (5), 1893, 1899,1903 (Box 4, Folder 176)
    - Ingley, Fred (Col.) (2), 1937 (Box 4, Folder 177)
    - Israel, Rogers 1854-1921, (Erie, Penn.) (8), 1911-1912, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 178)
    - Ives, Levi Silliman 1797-1867, (N.C.) (7), 1835-1836, 1843, 1850 (Box 4, Folder 179)
    - Ivins, Benjamin Franklin Price 1884-, (Milwaukee, Wisc.) (3), 1935, 1937, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 180)
    - Jackson, Henry Melville 1848-1900, (Ala.) (7), 1892-1894, 1896, 1896-1899 (Box 4, Folder 181)
    - Jaggar, Thomas Augustus 1839-1912, (S. Ohio) (8), 1897-1899, 1903-1905 (Box 4, Folder 182)
    - Jarvis, Abraham 1739-1813, (Conn.) (4), 1801 (Box 4, Folder 183)
      [Posthumous biographical sketch in "The Youth's Repository of Christian Knowledge," 1813]
    - Jenkins, Thomas 1871-, (Nev.) (2), 1929, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 184)
    - Jett, Robert Carter 1865-, (S. W.Va.) (3), 1937 (Box 4, Folder 185)
    - Johns, John 1796-1876, (Va.) (11), 1826, 1836, 1854, 1859, 1874, 1876, undated (Box 4, Folder 186)
    - Johnson, Frederick Foote 1866-, (Conn.; Mo.) (8), 1905, 1908-1909, 1921, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 187)
    - Johnson, Irving Peake 1866-, (Col.) (7), 1920, 1922, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 188)
    - Johnson, Joseph Harsfalls 1847-1928, (L.A., Cal.) (7), 1896, 1898, 1905, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 189)
    - Johnston, James Steptoe 1843-1924, (W. Texas) (8), 1889, 1899, 1903-1904, 1907-1908 (Box 4, Folder 190)
    - Jones, Everett H. (W. Texas) (1), 1949 (Box 4, Folder 191)
    - Jones, Paul 1880-, (Utah) (4), 1916, 1921, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 192)
    - Juhan, Frank Alexander (Fla.) (1), 1937 (Box 4, Folder 193)